Segun Idowu

343-297-9958

oluobamzy@gmail.com • Ottawa, Ontario

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Highly Effective visualization developer with over 3 years of transforming organizations using data insights. Known for helping teams to reach business goals and create value for companies and organizations. Very experienced in applying a wide variety of well-known data exploration techniques. My workflow starts from Identifying outliers, missing values, human error or biased sampling to Understanding importance of the variables and removing useless ones and then analysing the relationship between dataset features (variables) and ultimately, getting as much as possible from data and maximising the insights. With prior Skills in software development and interface design, working with teams whether onsite, distributed or remote is interesting to me. As an effective team leader (scrum master) employing metrics reporting skills to help teams, stakeholders and clients alike to have a broad overview of what work is being done and the overall health status of teams and projects. A passionate leader whose preference is value delivery all the time. Outside of work I am passionate about chess.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Data Analyst / Data Visualization Developer Intellectual House, Toronto, Ontario

May 2022

- Build compelling, interactive dashboards in Power BI for internal and external client deployment by consultants/managers
- Create Data Visualization Qlikview, and/or Spotfire solutions using leading technologies
- Educate the organization (starting with the Algorithms team, but extending into their internal business partners) on data communication and visualization best practices
- Lead a team of members to conduct business analysis, collect business requirements and translate them into BI Solution leveraging best practices
- Develop rich, interactive, visually striking graphics and data visualizations of "large" amounts
 of data that facilitate the presentation of data using different query methods in SQL
- Contribute to guidelines and user interface (UX) standards for interface design, visualization techniques, rich charting and analytic dashboards
- Collaborate with product development and user experience teams on UX design and storyboarding analytics information delivery use-cases

Scrum Master

May 2020 - March 2022

Beta Consulting Services, LLC • Maryland, United States

 Promoted and drove adoption of Agile Mindset (Drive Business Value, Deliver in Iterations, Collaboration) while ensuring all Salesforce updates made seamless move from development through staging to production.

- Managed all Scrum ceremonies, including Sprint Planning, daily Scrum Meetings, Sprint Reviews, and Sprint Retrospectives while conducting technical training sessions regarding Agile development methods.
- Continuously improved team performance by promoting joint accountability for results and solving productivity issues while facilitating and engaging in business analysis, user experience and technical conversations across platforms and multiple levels of influence.
- Worked with Product owner to groom product Backlog, story prioritization also helping to verify user stories with core team and ensure that all prioritized user stories have acceptance criteria

Data Analyst

Jan 2018 - Apr 2020

Wema Bank Plc, Lagos Nigeria

- Perform SQL queries
- Create data visualizations and dashboards using PowerBI
- Data Migration/ETL
- Analyze data and build visuals in spreadsheets
- Develop customer segmentation models

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Technology (Applied Mathematics)

Aug 2008 - Feb 2013

Ladoke Akintola University of Technology • Ogbomoso, Nigeria

SKILLS

- Confluence
- SQL Server
- SSMS
- Microsoft AZURE Data studio
- JIRA
- Continuous Integration/DeliveryCI/CD
- · Data Visualization
- Power BI CSS, HTML5, Javascript
- Business Requirements Elicitation
- · Relationship Management
- · Microsoft Office
- Mongo DB
- Git
- Trello

PROFESSIONAL CREDENTIALS

· Certified Scrum Professional, Scrum Alliance

- Data essentials professional, UTIVA inc
- UX Research professional, UTIVA inc